A Guide to the William Rockefeller family papers FA1098
Rockefeller Archive Center
William Rockefeller family papers
1860-1931
Rockefeller Archive Center
McAlpin, Emma Rockefeller
Rockefeller, William
Dodge, Geraldine R. (Geraldine Rockefeller) (1882-1973)
FA1098
9 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
A miscellaneous assortment of materials pertaining to William Rockefeller, his wife, his children and their descendants.
Arrangement
Arranged primarily by family member.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The William Rockefeller papers were donated in 1976.
- William Rockefeller family papers, 1860-1931; 1
  - Genealogy Documents, 1894-1897 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - William Rockefeller - Genealogy Book (Avery, Goodsell, Rockefeller) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - William Rockefeller - Corporate Tribute - Mechanics' National Bank, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - William Rockefeller - Corporate Tribute - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Rwy. Company, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - William Rockefeller - Corporate Tribute - Delaware, Lackawanna and Western RR. Company, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - William Rockefeller - Corporate Memorial - Anaconda Copper Mining Company and Brooklyn Union Gas Company, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - William Rockefeller - Corporate Memorial - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Rwy. Company, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - William Rockefeller - Corporate Memorial - New York Central RR. Company, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - William Rockefeller - Corporate Memorial - Rutland RR. Company, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Scope and Contents
    Notice of Probate.
  - William Rockefeller - Rockwood Hall - Inventory and Appraisal, Notice of Probate, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - William Rockefeller - Rockwood Hall - Villa Rockefeller - Prospectus, Article (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - William Rockefeller - Miscellaneous - Golden Wedding Anniversary poem; mausoleum; funeral, scrapbook, correspondence, 1893-1922 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Existence and Location of Originals
    Scrapbook including newspaper clippings removed to oversized box
  - Almira Goodsell Rockefeller - Memorial Service, 1796-10-10 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Almira Goodsell Rockefeller - Joel Goodsell - Land Deed, photostatic copy, 1920-01-21 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Correspondence, 1894-1895 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    on her engagement.
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Correspondence, 1918-1922 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    from her mother, condolences, domestics.
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Diaries, 1860; 1864 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Diaries, 1905-1909 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Diaries, 1910-1914 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Diaries, 1916-1920; 1921-1923 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Diaries, 1926-1930 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Checkbook - American Exchange Irving Trust Company, 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Checkbook - Farmers' Loan and Trust Company, 1917-1923 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Checkbook - First National Bank, Morristown, NJ, 1912-1922 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Checkbook - Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1918-1928 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Checkbook - Lincoln National Bank, 1905-1921 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Checkbook - National City Bank of New York, 1924-1928 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Checkbook, 1918-1919 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Checkbook, 1919-1921 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Disbursement Book, 1899-1903 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Financial - Bank Statements, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Financial Correspondence, Children's Accounts, Trusts, 1905-1906; 1908; 1920-1923; 1926-1927 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Ledger, 1918-1920 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Receipt Book, 1920-1925 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Genealogy Search (Goodsell, McAlpin, O'Brien), 1920-1933 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Travel Log, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Travel (Europe, Mediterranean), 1922; 1925 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Wedding Invitation List (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Booklawn Manor, New Jersey - Prospectus, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Miscellaneous - gold coin souvenir; correspondence; doll collection article; bills; Bible., 1895-1932 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Miscellaneous Books - Addresses (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Miscellaneous Books - Births, Deaths and Marriages (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Miscellaneous Books - Recettes de Cuisine (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin-Miscellaneous Book-Loose sheets from Recettes de Cuisine Recipe Book, 1896 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Miscellaneous Books - Country House, 1902-1903 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Miscellaneous Books, 1904 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin-Miscellaneous book- Garden Data, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - David Hunter McAlpin, Jr. - Bible (Box 8, Folder 48)
    Item removed to flat box of other bibles
  - David Hunter McAlpin III - Childhood Letters and Artwork, July 8, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Geraldine Rockefeller McAlpin Webster - Baby Book and photograph album, 1900-1905 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    Conditions Governing Access
    The baby book needs preservation
  - Geraldine Rockefeller McAlpin Webster - Correspondence and Miscellaneous, 1911-1939 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Geraldine Rockefeller McAlpin Webster - Poetry - Flights of Fancy, 1918-1937 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Geraldine Rockefeller McAlpin Webster - Travel Log - My Trip, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Jerome P. Webster - Correspondence with JDR Jr., 1934-1959 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Elaine McAlpin Tate, 1921 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Eliza Davison Rockefeller - Bible, 1862 (Box 10, Box 10A)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Bible, 1895 (Box 10, Box 10A)
  - David Hunter McAlpin, Jr. - Bible, 1914-1915 (Box 10, Box 10A)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Personal diaries and accounts, 1910-1922 (Box 10B)
  - William Rockefeller - Corporate Memorial, 1922-12-21 (Box 11)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin - Financial Correspondence, 1922-1923 (Box 11)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge - Scrapbook, 1865-1922 (Box 11)
  - Marcellus Hartley Dodge, Jr. - Memorial (Box 11)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge - Scrapbooks, 1931-1943 (Box 12, Volume 2)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge - Scrapbooks, 1930-1942 (Box 13, Volume 1)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge - Scrapbooks, 1933-1941 (Box 14)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge-Scrapbooks, 1931-1943; 3 Bound Volumes Oversized box (Box 15, Volume 3)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge-Diaries, 1896-1960 (Box 16)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge-Clippings, Poetry and Correspondence, 1914-1962 (Box 17, Folder 56)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge-Correspondence, 1916-1921 (Box 17, Folder 57)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge, Marcellus Hartley Dodge-Correspondence, 1922-1954 (Box 17, Folder 58)
  - Family Genealogy-John D. Rockefeller Jr., 1948-1953 (Box 17, Folder 59)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge -Finances and Loans, 1938-1941 (Box 17, Folder 60)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge-Newspaper Clippings Genealogy, 1878-1975 (Box 17, Folder 61)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge-Newspaper Clippings, 1916-1928 (Box 17, Folder 62)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge- Rockefeller Family Data-Family Genealogy, 1841-1961 (Box 17, Folder 63)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge-Rockefeller Genealogy Goodsell Family, 1887-1952 (Box 17, Folder 64)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge-Family Record Book-Genealogy, 1950-1969 (Box 17, Folder 65)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge-Memorial Plaque for Marcellus Hartley Dodge, Jr., 1931 (Box 17, Folder 66)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge-Genealogy Goodsell Family Bound Journal, 1938 (Box 17, Folder 67)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge-Scrapbook, 1933-1940 (Box 18, Volume 4)
  - William Rockefeller-Rockwood Hall Photographs (Box 19)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge-Memorial Plaque for Marcellus Hartley Dodge, Jr., 1931 (Box 20)